So you're the CEO of one of
the largest solar companies in the entire country.
So what has been the most amount of
money that you've ever made in a single year?
My business has done, did $149 million last
year and we should do double that this year.
So you're on track to
do about $300 million this year?
Correct.
Meet Zane Jane.
Over the last four years, he's built one
of the largest solar companies in the entire world
and become one of the most
successful entrepreneurs across the United States.
However, it didn't start out that way.
Zane grew up living in poverty and
was a son to two immigrant parents,
but he decided he ultimately wanted
to create a new destiny for himself.
And through learning the ins and
outs and mastering the game of entrepreneurship,
at 16 years old, he started his first business.
By the time he was 19, he dropped
out of school and at 20 years old,
he had built a multi-million dollar company.
Fast forward to now at 27 years old,
the company he started from scratch is
on track to do $300 million this year.
In this interview, Zane revealed to me some
of the most lucrative secrets to creating wealth
that he's learned as a nine-figure
entrepreneur that school will not teach you.
I'm James Dumoulin and this is Questions with Millionaires.
All right, you guys, welcome
back to Questions with Multi-Millionaires.
We've got a very special guest today, Zane,
who's the CEO of a massive
solar company out here in Miami, Florida.
And before we get into some questions today,
Zane, give us a little
bit of your background, your story,
and what all you're working on right now.
Yeah, so I'm the CEO of a solar company.
I have over 600 W2 employees, over
3,000 sales reps that sell through us,
and we're one of the largest
residential solar installers in the country.
However, that's not how I started.
I started growing up.
You know, lower class.
My family didn't speak English.
They were first-generation immigrants to this country.
And yeah, you know, life's always been really hard.
But at 18 years old, I decided to
make a decision to go all into sales,
master the art of sales.
That's what led me to get into solar sales.
And fast forward, I went from being a
salesperson, a sales leader to a business owner.
And here we are today.
That's incredible.
So you're the CEO of one of
the largest solar companies in the entire country.
So what has been the most amount of
money that you've ever made in a single year?
My business has done, did 149 million last
year, and we should do double that this year.
So you're on track to
do about 300 million this year?
Correct. Yeah.
What was the biggest thing that you've implemented in your
business to take it from not only seven to eight,
but eventually eight to nine figures?
A lot of people in today's
world, they'll have a great idea.
They'll start that business, but
they struggle to scale and grow.
What's been your secret to scaling your
business to where it's now a nine-figure company?
To get to seven figures, you need a
really good idea and really good sales and marketing.
To get to eight figures,
you need a really good team.
If you have the right people,
If you have the right people around you,
you'll be able to get to eight figures.
But to get to nine figures is
one of the hardest things to do.
You not only need a really good product, you
need really great marketing, you need really great sales,
you need a really great team,
but most importantly, you need systems.
You need SOPs, standard operating procedures.
In my company, there's a standard
operating procedure for everything we do.
And this is a little bit of a joke
and exaggerated, but there's legitimately a standard operating procedure
if you want to go to the
bathroom or if you want to make coffee.
The whole point of that
is for every system and function,
every function in the business, it has to be documented.
Because if it is documented, that
means that if I get sick today,
I can pass my colleague that document
and they can actually do my work function.
So therefore, you are no longer relying on me.
And when you are an eight-figure business owner, a
lot of times, people are still relying on the CEO.
But when you become a nine-figure business owner,
people aren't just relying on the CEO anymore.
They're relying on the machine and the system.
So the CEO could die, but the
machine and the system will continue to scale.
So to me, that's where most
people get stuck at that eight-figure range.
That's incredible.
There's a famous quote that says,
the poor get poorer and the rich often get richer.
But for someone who may be
stuck in that cycle of poverty, right?
You, for example, you didn't
come from a lot of money.
At all, yeah.
Exactly.
And so for someone who
may be stuck in that cycle,
what do you recommend to them to
really break out of that cycle of poverty
and they want to become successful and
maybe build a successful company like their...
Number one, you can't get
rich being in a poor environment.
So make enough money to move.
That's it.
If you're in a poor
environment, you're going to stay poor.
I don't care what anyone says.
You're not going to build a
billion-dollar business living in a lower-class neighborhood.
It's just not going to happen.
You're just not going to have the mental fortitude.
You're not going to have the
ability to meet the right people.
You're not going to have any connections.
You're going to go out there.
You're going to be demotivated and depressed.
Why?
Because you're in a shit hole
at the end of the day.
So if you're 14, 15, work on your
skills because you got no choice until you're 18.
You know that you're in there,
but as soon as you turn 18,
you're ready to go.
You're ready to move out of your
home because you've built up some money.
You've invested in skill sets.
Maybe you got really good at sales and marketing.
Now you've made enough to move into a bigger city like
Miami or Boston or New York or Los Angeles or Dubai.
You can move into a city
and you look around and you're like,
dude, there's hundreds of billions of dollars
in this city just sitting here right now.
In this one city.
I come from this small little town that's a shit
hole, but in this city, it all exists out there.
So I got to get closer to the money.
Right?
If I grew up in an
environment where everyone's making 40K a year,
well, I'm not really close to the money.
I'm close to everyone making 40 grand a year.
If I go into a city and there's
a pretty good chance within a 30 mile radius,
I have 14 billionaires and I
have tens of thousands of multimillionaires.
Well now, if I want to build a business in
that area and I want to get money, what am I?
I'm closer to the money.
So the chances of me
making more money are significantly higher.
So if you're stuck in that rat race,
you're stuck in the situation of
poverty or your paycheck to paycheck,
do everything you can to save your money,
not to go and invest in real estate
or the stock market or something of that nature.
But first thing you should invest in is yourself
and the best thing that you can invest in.
And this is before anything else.
The only thing I would put before this
is like maybe your education and yourself and,
you know, go and buy a sales course or a marketing course
and become a good Facebook ads guy or a good high ticket closer.
Sure.
Those are skillsets you can invest in.
But before buying the nicest car or the
nicest watch or those clothes that you like
or even buying gifts for your friends and family,
invest your money into moving to a
place where every day when you walk outside,
you have a view and you
have a view of a city.
You have a view of money.
You have a view of an economy that's moving.
You guys were just telling me, oh, we love
being in Miami because there's so much stuff going on.
Yeah. Imagine driving out in the city and you see this and you
see that guy and you see that car and you see that business.
And you see that celebrity.
You start to get inspired and
it makes you want to work harder.
But if I walk outside and all
I see is a beat down tennis court,
I see a beat down park.
I see all these homes with broken
windows, people walking around in the postman.
Like I'm not I'm not excited.
I'm not happy.
I'm not motivated.
I just want to go back home and I want to play
Xbox because that's way more exciting to me than walking outside my house.
But when I walk outside, I'm like, dude,
I no longer need to play Grand Theft Auto.
Why? Because I live in
Grand Theft Auto every single day.
And that's the mentality you need to have.
And that's what listen, like
I'm just I'm being very real.
Like when I was 14, I needed to hear that because I was stuck
in that environment and I got so lucky that I left at 18 years old.
It was not a plan.
But if I had just stayed comfortable and I did not move away from where I was,
I'm convinced if I just stayed there for two or three more years, I never would have left.
And that would have changed my entire life.
And no one would know who I was today.
Wow.
It's incredible.
That was a phenomenal answer from Zane and
his best business game is yet to come.
But I want to take a quick
second to thank AG1 for sponsoring this video.
As you all know, we're always traveling the
country to deliver this content for you guys.
And because of that, it can be very challenging to make
sure I get the right amount of nutrients in during the day.
Drinking AG1 has been the foundational nutrient habit that
I needed, especially while on the going on workout days.
It replenishes my daily micronutrients.
It's been crucial for my routine.
AG1 travel packs make it easy to stay committed to your
intentions wherever you are and when you need it the most.
Running a full-time business can be stressful at times.
And drinking AG1 has been great
for reducing stress and boosting mental clarity.
AG1 helps me keep sustained energy
throughout the day and improve my focus.
AG1 has been a game changer.
So make sure you go to
drinkag1.com-theschoolofhardknocks to get started on your order.
AG1 is going to give our community a free one-year supply of AG vitamin
D3 and K2 and five AG1 travel packs for free with your first purchase.
So thank you to AG1 for sponsoring this video.
And with that being said, let's get back to Zayn.
You know, what's been the importance of surrounding
yourself with the right people throughout your career?
You know, how have you really been
able to leverage relationships in the business world?
And what advice would you give to
someone who's really trying to build that network?
Maybe they don't have the best interpersonal skills, but they
want to get really better at networking, connecting with people.
What's been the importance of it for you?
And what do you recommend to someone
who's trying to get better at that?
The hard truth is no one will give
a fuck about you if you don't have something.
It's a hard truth.
Like, very rarely do you run into someone that's very
successful that's just like a super nice guy and is like,
Listen, I don't know who you are.
You're from the street, blah, blah, blah.
You're not successful, but I'm going to take you on.
I'm going to teach you everything.
Not because they're not nice people, but to their right, they have
to focus on what's going to add a value in their life.
And if you are a human being that does not
provide value, there's no reason that someone should give you value.
So when people ask me, I'm like,
I'm not going to give you value.
So when people, people always ask me this question because I am
a phenomenal networker and I know almost everyone and I have great relationships,
friendships with athletes, celebrities, CEOs,
business owners, Fortune 100 owners.
And how I got there wasn't
by just being in the right rooms.
That's a part of it.
But how did I get into the right rooms?
Well, I built myself up so that
one day someone invited me into those rooms.
Now, when I get into that
room, I can have that conversation.
And they know that most likely if you're in
that room, you're going to be in that room.
You're someone of high caliber and stature.
So you can hold a conversation with them and
you can talk to them about things that are relatable.
And what do I do when I'm
around someone that's more successful than me?
And this happens to me quite frequently.
I shut up.
I don't ask them a million questions.
I don't ask them for advice.
I don't ask them to help me.
Not because I don't want it, but because I
know I have not earned their respect or value yet.
I have to get them to come to
me willingly and want to pour it onto me.
So I will always just be there.
I will either talk about fun stuff, stuff that
I know that's going to engage and excite them,
or I'm going to give them back tons of value
or ask them if I can do something for them.
But the real question is, 18-year-old Zane, he was
never going to meet the people that he's met today.
And he wasn't just going to walk up to
them, run into them, and build a great connection.
Even if you do, even if you run into a
billionaire in the street, you run into Elon in the street,
you meet him, you get to do a
video with him, you get to talk to him.
That's cool, right?
And maybe it's great for content and
maybe it changes your life in that way.
But there's no way that
Elon's giving you your phone number.
There's no way that he's answering
your call or talking to you.
So you've got to work
your way up to that point.
So I would just recommend work on yourself.
Become a more valuable version.
And if you want to be around more valuable
people, you have to value yourself and become valuable.
That's number one.
Number two is it's not just
about who you hang out with.
It's about who you don't hang out with.
That's the really important factor.
If I'm around a group of
bums that don't take care of themselves,
aren't successful, don't work on themselves,
are always getting fucked up and partying and doing drugs,
well, not only am I eventually going to
become like that if I keep hanging around them,
but other people are going to be like,
I don't want to hang around Zane.
Not because Zane's not a great guy,
but because the four buddies that
he's hanging around are bringing him down.
They don't provide any value to our group,
so I'm not even going to invite him because
I know he's going to be with his four buddies.
And that happens to people every day.
Unfortunately, it happens to people that know me.
I don't want to hang out
with them, not because of them,
but because I know the crew
that they bring along with them
brings a massive amount of negativity.
And this has nothing to do
with financial success, by the way.
I'm not looking at that in any case.
I know a lot of people
that are extremely financially well off,
but they entertain in drugs
all day, they party every weekend.
So I just know, like, dude, I'm
not trying to hang out with the guy
that's going to go out with us tonight
and is going to have a line of Coke.
It's not in my environment anymore.
I'm over that stuff.
I did that stuff when I was younger.
I'm at a point in my life where
I only want to surround myself with people
that are very positive and are all focused on growth.
When I sit at a dinner table with my friends,
I want those conversations to be about
how are we going to help each other?
How are we all going to make more money?
What's this crazy new idea?
I was talking to my buddy the other day.
His name is Dr. D. He's a great Miami doctor,
one of the best celebrity doctors in the world.
And he was telling me
about this invention that he had.
He had this insane, crazy invention.
We were talking about it, and I was like, dude,
one day when you come up
with that, and you make it,
and you make that prototype, I will invest in you,
and I want to build that idea with you.
Those are the type of conversations
that I want at my dinner table.
I don't want like, bro, did you see that girl?
Dude, did you see this fucking thing?
Did you go to this party?
Did you talk to this person?
It's like, this stuff is bullshit.
There's no substance there.
There's no value there.
I want conversations with value.
So like I said, it's not
just about who you hang around with
and what rooms you get in, but
it's who you don't hang around with.
So you've got hundreds of millions
of dollars coming into the company
that you're dealing with.
Correct.
What is the best financial advice that you ever received
throughout your lifetime?
If there's one lesson that a
mentor or somebody taught you about money
that's always stuck for you, what is that advice?
Spend your money.
Everyone is going to be like, what?
Everyone says save your money.
Save your money.
Hoard it in the bank account.
No, the only way that you can
build something is by pouring into it.
It's like, imagine if you had
a brand new Bugatti parked downstairs,
but there was no gas tank to put fuel in,
so you literally couldn't drive it.
That's exactly what a bank account is like.
You have a $5 million bank account
that's not working for you.
It's literally like a Bugatti with no gasoline.
You can't drive it.
It's like an art piece.
You're just going to look at it,
and it's going to deteriorate in value every single year.
So what I tell business owners,
and this is the biggest
mistake that so many people make,
is when you have money in your bank account,
do not look at it as something to protect you.
Look at it as something to make you more money
and make you more successful.
I get so anxious when
we look at our bank account
and there's so much money in there.
Why?
Because I'm like, what are we doing with this?
We don't need this right now.
We have all of our expenses, our operating costs,
everything is taken care of, payroll is made.
Let's put this money to work.
Because if I can put that money to work,
I'm going to do two things.
Number one, I'm going to
create more value in my business,
which is the most important and
essential thing that I can do.
Why?
Because a majority of my
net worth lies in my business.
So every dollar I'm putting in,
it's just going into building this asset
that holds a majority of my net worth.
Number two is, it makes you operate differently
as a business.
When you're cush as a business,
and you know that you have money
that makes you feel comfortable,
you don't necessarily make the same decisions.
Maybe you could have made your business
a little bit more efficient and profitable,
but you didn't because you knew
that you had this savings, right?
Or maybe you needed to
go and hit this sales target,
but you didn't push your team far enough.
Why?
Because you had this cushion
and you had this money saved.
But when you're constantly reinvesting your money
back into your business and into yourself,
well, you end up draining your bank account.
What do you got to do?
You got to keep making it over and over again.
So those are my fundamentals and principles with money.
I will never ever hoard my money.
I will always put it back into something.
So my next question for you,
you sold hundreds of millions of dollars in revenue
throughout your career, probably billions now.
What's been your secret to sales throughout your career?
How have you been able to consistently sell your products
at a high volume,
regardless of the industries that you've been in?
I don't care what anyone says.
You could have amazing persuasion tactics.
You could learn NLP, by the way.
I hate NLP.
You could learn all of these different skills and tactics.
There's one thing in sales that will make you beat
every other salesperson,
and that's conviction in your product.
If you believe in your
product, you don't need a script.
You don't need special training.
You don't need objection handling.
Now, don't get me wrong.
Those things are important.
All of my sales guys have a script.
All of them handle objections.
All of them do role plays.
That's not what I'm saying.
What I'm saying is the tactics are 10%
of it.
90% of it is believing in your product.
If I had two salespeople next to me,
one of them trained tactics, objections,
but didn't believe in the product.
The other one, zero training, absolute rookie,
but believed in the product.
I take the person that believes in the product
10 times out of 10.
Why?
Because conviction is everything.
When you're sitting in front of a sales cycle
or you're on the phone,
people can feel your enthusiasm,
your excitement, and your belief in your product.
And if they don't feel it,
they will not buy.
So whenever I look at a salesperson,
I'm never judging them by how they talk
or what they say.
I'm judging them by what's their conviction
and belief in their product.
And I don't need a special tool to measure that.
I don't need them to say something perfectly.
I just need to look at them face to face.
And I can tell you in any salesperson
with any product,
I can tell you whether they believe
in their product or not.
So whenever I'm walking down my sales floor
or I'm looking at different salespeople,
I'm looking at them and I'm like,
I'm not sure what they're saying.
I'm not looking at their customers
or their corporate salespeople.
I'm always looking at that
and I'm asking them questions like,
hey, why are you selling?
What do you like about the product?
And whenever I hear
super short-sighted, short-term beliefs
or I see them go up against barriers and walls
and start to believe their customer's objections,
it just means one thing,
they don't believe in their product.
So what would you say
is the biggest difference
between the wealthy and the rich?
Like what's the number one thing
that separates the rich from the wealthy?
Wealthy people,
it depends what rich is, right?
Some people,
rich in my book making four to five to ten million
dollars a year is rich that's what i view as rich
wealthy you're a billionaire that's that's it like
to me there's nothing under a billion that
categorizes you as truly wealthy so what do i mean by
that well i grew up in a town that you know
people if you made 100 grand in a
year you literally were considered like wealthy like
people would drop the w word to me today you
have four or five million dollars that could be gone
in a year or two i have so many friends that
can spend that in two to three months right four to
five million dollars is legitimately nothing when
you are building a massive business or you're
going out there and you're creating wealth what
really matters is what are you doing with your
wealth as we just talked about so when i look
at wealthy it's the ability to actually not just have
a high net worth but when i say someone
has a billion dollars like they genuinely have a billion
dollars in assets they have money that
is deployed whether it's into businesses private equity
the stock market real estate different assets
around the world they have their money poured
into and their money's working for them and i
truly view that as wealthy because when you have
a billion dollars there's very little things that you
can do on this planet that will hurt your bank
account or put you in a rough financial position you
can go and buy a 50 million dollar yacht you
can buy a 50 million dollar plane you can have
six houses around the world and it will not affect
your billion dollar net worth
however contrary to popular belief
a lot of people would think that about 100
million dollars well you can't have a 50 million dollar
yacht if you're worth 100 million dollars why
because it's going to cost you over 12 million
dollars a year just to operate that that's 12
of your net worth that you're putting into one thing
that's essentially a toy that will not make you more
money so people just you know and i say this
not out of arrogance but out of when i was 16
years old i thought a few hundred grand was a lot
of money and i wish that there was someone like
me telling me like dude don't set a hundred thousand
dollar target don't set a million dollar target and
i'm like dude you're not gonna make me $100,000
dollar target don't set a hundred million dollar
target knowing who zayn is and knowing that zayn
wants to be the best in the world
set a multi-billion dollar target and always go bigger
all right so you know my last question for
you man you obviously put yourself in a multi-million
dollar property you built a nine-figure company any
last words of advice to the younger generation
out there of entrepreneurs who may be watching
this aspiring to you know eventually build a
company like yourself and kind of live this
lifestyle learn sales and never give up those
are the only two things
why because those are the two things that
have changed my life i'm an excellent communicator
and that's because i learned sales i learned
the inside and the outs of communicating with
the human being and when you can learn that
you will be successful no matter where you go it's
number one number two it's going to be really hard
it's going to be a lot of roadblocks there's going
to be a lot of people that tell you that it's
not going to work it's gonna be a lot of times where
you feel like giving up do not quit as long
as you learn sales and you don't quit promise you
can get whatever you want in this world amazing and
uh saying thank you so much for being with us
on the show man thank you and where can
everybody find out more about you and what all you're
working on right now at zane jan on all my social
media you can find me online and or you can type
in my name on google and you'll see me everybody
go tap in with zane thank you so much for watching
this video be sure to leave a
like and subscribe for tons of amazing content
and click right here to watch
our full interview with grant cardone